Tan Yu Hui

Mobile: 8126 9990 | Email: yuhui tan@mymail.sutd.edu.sg |

Portfolio: https://yuhuitan.github.io/

PERSONAL PROFILE

A highly self-motivated undergraduate majoring in Information Systems Technology and Design. Creative team-player with plenty of working experience in various fields. Highly adaptable in different working environments, with strong communication skills to work with colleagues of different nationalities and races. Fast learner who is interested in the areas of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Interaction Design, UI/UX, Usability and Ergonomics, as well as information systems. Sensitive to end-user and usability issues while also equipped with software engineering and system integration skills.

EDUCATION

Singapore University of Technology and Design (May 2016 – Present)

- Bachelor of Engineering (Information Systems Technology and Design), Honours
- Cybersecurity Specialization
- Expected Graduation August 2019

WORKING EXPERIENCES

GRABTAXI HOLDINGS PTE. LTD.

May 2018 – August 2018

Cybersecurity Intern

- Worked closely with the GrabPay and Infosec Team to develop GrabPay Admiral, an
 application which will be used on the backend of GrabPay which detects fraudulent
 behaviour.
- At the end of the internship, produced a fully documented research paper on device fingerprinting, which will be used as the foundation of building fingerprinting systems like GrabPay Admiral in Grab's ecosystem.
- Formulated possible use cases for GrabPay Admiral, identified potential flaws and drawbacks and counter-produced relevant solutions for these issues.
- Researched extensively in the areas of mobile application frauds, and parameters that can be exploited to profile fraudulent behaviour.
- Constructed relevant flowcharts that can be used as guidelines for onboarding new vendors into Grab's ecosystem.

POLICYPAL

May 2017 – August 2017

Business Development Intern

- Acquiring new users for PolicyPal's phone application. Over the course of internship, increased user database by 30%.
- Represented the company for career fairs at NUS and SMU, technology seminars hosted by e27 and Tech in Asia, and showcased our product at an AIG mini conference.
- Represented the company for a pitching competition to a group of investors in Lattice80 (largest Fintech hub in Singapore recognised by the Monetary Authority of Singapore).
- Made use of Google AdWords and Facebook Marketing to manage and analyse the company's marketing spending, which resulted in 40% growth of sales over 3 months.
- Liaised with companies such as WOOFR and Deliveroo for various partnerships.

- Content creation for content marketing.
- Assisted in the company's Search Engine Optimization (SEO) strategies, to optimize landing pages and content recommendation for organic SEO success.

YY HONG YE GROUP PTE LTD

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

Recruitment Consultant

- Provided staff support for 2 existing clients, enabling events to function smoothly, picking up a higher percentage of clients' staff support share.
- Helped resolve issues between supported staffs and clients, preventing disputes and thus allowing clients' events to function smoothly.
- Collaborated with company's Manager to set up company profile, and successfully bringing in a new client, raising company's profit.
- Maintaining good relationship between recruited staffs, allowing staffs to work in a friendly environment and boosted company's reputations within clients.

LUXE SYDNEY SINGAPORE

May 2016

Waiter

- Basic stock-checking and tidying of spaces, ensuring that colleagues working in the following shifts can have a conducive place to work in.
- Great communication skills and service, ensuring customers enjoy their stay, henceforth being complimented for good service on the first day of work, and many others in subsequent weeks.

HUMMING FLOWERS & GIFTS PTE LTD

Nov 2011 - Jan 2012

Telecomm Salesperson

- Helping customers by choosing appropriate products as gifts, and making a number of loyal customers within the 2 months stay in the job.
- Friendly and responsible communication skills earned compliments from superiors and customers likewise, acquiring pay increment with just 2 weeks into the job.
- In peak periods, taking up the side job of delivering voluntarily, easing the company's functional stress, allowing company to sail through the peak period smoothly.

RECENT PROJECTS

SMILE App

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Produced a fully functional wireframe of a dental mobile app on Adobe XD, that tackles key efficiency concepts of user interface design
- Systematically explored the trade-off between efficiency and learnability to frame the design problem and solution space
- Conducted an iterative, term-long design/implementation process with a series of brainstorming, literature review, sketching exercises, low-/high-fidelity prototyping, usability testing with 32 participants, analysis and extraction of insights for design refinement.
- Managed to save up to 85% of time spent on appointment booking functions compared to traditional appointment booking methods in the market

Flight Insurance DApp Project

Sept 2018 – Dec 2018

- Produced an end-user web application with the purpose of allowing customers to purchase flight tickets using cryptocurrency and allows on-the-spot claiming for insurances.
- This decentralized application was designed using knowledge from blockchain, with the backbone being smart contracts designed using Solidity.
- Front-end design included the study of usability to ensure consistent, intuitive and easy-to-learn user-interface.

SUTD-Y: Scheduling and Productivity Mobile App for Institutions Jan 2018 – May 2018

- Spearheaded a team of 4 to develop a one-stop solution for efficient scheduling as well as communication between professors and students.
- Undertaking the responsibilities of the app's user interface and user experience, then producing a smooth-running app that is intuitive to use.

OTHER PROJECTS

CIMB NIAGA 3D CONQUEST HACKATHON

Dec 2018

- Worked in a team with two other schoolmates to propose a solution to aid the unbanked population of Indonesia
- 1 of 5 teams from Singapore that made it to the semi-finals.
- Pitched and came up for the main wireframe for the mobile application

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Proficient in Python and Java programming languages
- Basic knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript programming languages
- Versed in Microsoft Word and Microsoft Excel
- Proficient in Adobe XD for Application Wireframing
- Search Engine Marketing on Facebook and Google AdWords
- Copywriting and Content Marketing
- Basic Search Engine Optimization
- Basic skills in Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Fluent in English and Mandarin (Spoken and written)
- Fluent in the Hokkien dialect
- Outgoing personality who enjoys communicating with different individuals